<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-27T19:10:17+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">alexander ilg microblog</title><subtitle>Just some things that come to my mind</subtitle><entry><title type="html">With the small VW ID.3 to Berlin</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/electric/2022/04/27/With-VW-ID3-to-Berlin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="With the small VW ID.3 to Berlin" /><published>2022-04-27T18:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T18:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/electric/2022/04/27/With-VW-ID3-to-Berlin</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/electric/2022/04/27/With-VW-ID3-to-Berlin.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I drove with my <strong>VW ID.3</strong> from Augsburg to Berlin. About 600 km with just two charging stops.</p>

<p>In general the car - even with the small 58kW battery - is able to perform on such a distance. There are just a number of things that I don’t like: (1) The main display on the dashboard looks like it belongs to a toy car. No sign of the elegance of a Tesla, Audi or BMW. (2) When I set the speed to 100 km/h, it contstantly switches: 99 to 100 to 99 to 100 to … it drives me crazy. (3) The way the doors are locked. I don’t get it - I always have to press the button on the car key multiple times before the charging port opens or I am able to open the trunk.</p>

<p>Other than that, the car is just fine.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="electric" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I drove with my VW ID.3 from Augsburg to Berlin. About 600 km with just two charging stops. In general the car - even with the small 58kW battery - is able to perform on such a distance. There are just a number of things that I don’t like: (1) The main display on the dashboard looks like it belongs to a toy car. No sign of the elegance of a Tesla, Audi or BMW. (2) When I set the speed to 100 km/h, it contstantly switches: 99 to 100 to 99 to 100 to … it drives me crazy. (3) The way the doors are locked. I don’t get it - I always have to press the button on the car key multiple times before the charging port opens or I am able to open the trunk. Other than that, the car is just fine.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">People Business</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/25/people-business.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People Business" /><published>2022-04-25T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-25T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/25/people-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/25/people-business.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am developing, selling, and implementing software since more than 20 years. During that time, I participated in many requests for proposal, many sales pitches and I competed against a lot of competitors. You might think that the best software always wins, but that is not the case. Many times, I heard things like <strong><em>“we choose you because you made the most competent impression”</em></strong> or <strong><em>“you worked hardest during the POC”</em></strong>.</p>

<p>This shows that it is at least 50% people business. Your impression as a software provider is as important as your software. I learned this very early in my career. I was hired by a company in Cologne, Germany to evaluate several e-commerce providers for a new website - among them Oracle and SAP. After the evaluation it was clear to me that Oracle has the far better software based on J2EE, while SAP was pitching it proprietary ITS technology. At the end they still went with SAP. Why? Because the sales pitch was superior to the one from Oracle (they showed up totally unprepared) and the CIO told me <strong><em>“The way they showed up here and pitched the solutions, the same way they will do the implementation. I have no good feeling with Oracle”</em></strong>.</p>

<p>I think that I make a good impression most of the time and I see that as a competitive advantage. COVID hurt in that regard, as there were no face-to-face meetings. Let’s hope we are soon back to onsite sales demos.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/corona.jpg" alt="jorganizer" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="business" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am developing, selling, and implementing software since more than 20 years. During that time, I participated in many requests for proposal, many sales pitches and I competed against a lot of competitors. You might think that the best software always wins, but that is not the case. Many times, I heard things like “we choose you because you made the most competent impression” or “you worked hardest during the POC”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">jorganizer - first steps in Java</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/backinthedays/2022/04/24/jorganizer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="jorganizer - first steps in Java" /><published>2022-04-24T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-24T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/backinthedays/2022/04/24/jorganizer</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/backinthedays/2022/04/24/jorganizer.html"><![CDATA[<p>Until 2001 I was mainly developing in <strong>Perl</strong>, but I wanted to get into the <strong>Java</strong> space (which was a smart move, as it got me a job as Java developer at <strong>SAP</strong>).</p>

<p>How do you best learn a new language? Going through tutorials is only working until a certain point, then I need to get my hands dirty and do a real project.</p>

<p>In 2002, I started to write a webbased PIM with Java, running on a Tomcat server - it was called <strong>jorganizer</strong> and I shared it on SourceForge. The <a href="http://jorganizer.sourceforge.net/index.html">website</a> is still up today, but I didn’t touch it the last 20 years.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/jorganizer.jpg" alt="jorganizer" /></p>

<p>This was at a time when we dealed with <strong>Microsoft Internet Explorer</strong> and <strong>Netscape Navigator</strong>, a time where PNG was not yet available. At least I am sure it is not useing <strong><em>Log4J</em></strong> ;-)</p>

<p>I wonder if the code would still run today on a modern tomcat.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="backinthedays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Until 2001 I was mainly developing in Perl, but I wanted to get into the Java space (which was a smart move, as it got me a job as Java developer at SAP). How do you best learn a new language? Going through tutorials is only working until a certain point, then I need to get my hands dirty and do a real project. In 2002, I started to write a webbased PIM with Java, running on a Tomcat server - it was called jorganizer and I shared it on SourceForge. The website is still up today, but I didn’t touch it the last 20 years. This was at a time when we dealed with Microsoft Internet Explorer and Netscape Navigator, a time where PNG was not yet available. At least I am sure it is not useing Log4J ;-) I wonder if the code would still run today on a modern tomcat.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Germans turn their kids into little Psychopaths</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/fun/2022/04/22/Struwwelpeter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Germans turn their kids into little Psychopaths" /><published>2022-04-22T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-22T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/fun/2022/04/22/Struwwelpeter</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/fun/2022/04/22/Struwwelpeter.html"><![CDATA[<p>From very young age, German kids hear stories that turn them into little psychopaths. It worked with me.</p>

<p>On the one side, there are fary tails like <strong>Little Red Riding Hood</strong>, where a wolf eats humans or Hensel &amp; Gretel, where a witch plans to eat children. I guess these stories are now also internationally very popular, but let me introduce you to a book that my mother and grandmother used to read to me when I was three years old:</p>

<h2 id="struwwelpeter">Struwwelpeter</h2>

<p>(Peter with the messy hair)
<img src="/assets/struwwelpeter/struwwelpeter.jpg" alt="Struwwelpeter" /></p>

<p>It contains stories that should teach children to listen to their parents. Funny stuff if you are not a small child.</p>

<p>There is the story about the boy that always sucks on his thumbs, even his mother tells him to stop. He still does it while his mother is not home, but if you do that kids, his guy will come and cut off both your thumbs:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/struwwelpeter/daumenlutscher.jpg" alt="Daumenlutscher" /></p>

<p>Or this nice story about Kasper, who did not want to eat his soup. After 5 days, he starved to death. I wish I could loose weight so fast.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/struwwelpeter/suppenkasper.jpg" alt="Suppenkasper" /></p>

<p>Finally, this poor girl was playing with a lighter and guess what - she burned to death.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/struwwelpeter/feuer.jpg" alt="Feuer" /></p>

<p>Now you know why we started two world wars and invented software like SAP …</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="fun" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From very young age, German kids hear stories that turn them into little psychopaths. It worked with me. On the one side, there are fary tails like Little Red Riding Hood, where a wolf eats humans or Hensel &amp; Gretel, where a witch plans to eat children. I guess these stories are now also internationally very popular, but let me introduce you to a book that my mother and grandmother used to read to me when I was three years old:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/movilitas/2022/04/21/judgeTheCharacterOfAMan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-21T15:32:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-21T15:32:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/movilitas/2022/04/21/judgeTheCharacterOfAMan</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/movilitas/2022/04/21/judgeTheCharacterOfAMan.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="you-can-easily-judge-the-character-of-a-man-by-how-he-treats-those-who-can-do-nothing-for-him">You Can Easily Judge the Character of a Man by How He Treats Those Who Can Do Nothing for Him</h2>

<p>I just experienced it this week - it is a valuable lesson and good to be reminded.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="movilitas" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You Can Easily Judge the Character of a Man by How He Treats Those Who Can Do Nothing for Him I just experienced it this week - it is a valuable lesson and good to be reminded.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Connecting SAP Cloud Integration with Salesforce</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/sap-cloud-integration/2022/04/21/SalesforceIntegrationWithSAP-CI.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Connecting SAP Cloud Integration with Salesforce" /><published>2022-04-21T14:52:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-21T14:52:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/sap-cloud-integration/2022/04/21/SalesforceIntegrationWithSAP-CI</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/sap-cloud-integration/2022/04/21/SalesforceIntegrationWithSAP-CI.html"><![CDATA[<p>I found an excellent blog, that describes how <strong>SAP Cloud Integration</strong> can be used to integrate into <strong>Salesforce</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/SAP-CloudIntegration-with-Saleforce.jpg" alt="SAP Cloud Integration" /></p>

<p>This looks unnecessary complex to me. I have never worked with SAP Cloud Integration, but with a number of other integration tools, where I did a lot more (real life integration of complex business processes) than what is shown in this blog and it was much simpler. But I guess SAP customers are used to this and don’t question it. In 2022, software should be better than this!</p>

<p>The two parts of the blog can be found here:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://blogs.sap.com/2021/05/21/sap-cloud-integration-with-salesforce/">SAP Cloud Integration with Salesforce – Part 1</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://blogs.sap.com/2021/06/20/sap-cloud-integration-with-salesforce-part-2/">SAP Cloud Integration with Salesforce – Part 2</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sap-cloud-integration" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I found an excellent blog, that describes how SAP Cloud Integration can be used to integrate into Salesforce. This looks unnecessary complex to me. I have never worked with SAP Cloud Integration, but with a number of other integration tools, where I did a lot more (real life integration of complex business processes) than what is shown in this blog and it was much simpler. But I guess SAP customers are used to this and don’t question it. In 2022, software should be better than this! The two parts of the blog can be found here: SAP Cloud Integration with Salesforce – Part 1 SAP Cloud Integration with Salesforce – Part 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SAP - still inconsistent after 50 years</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/sap/2022/04/21/sap-gui-inconsistency.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SAP - still inconsistent after 50 years" /><published>2022-04-21T07:42:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-21T07:42:00+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/sap/2022/04/21/sap-gui-inconsistency</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/sap/2022/04/21/sap-gui-inconsistency.html"><![CDATA[<p>I know that I am complaining about small, minor things here, but please explain me this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/sap-s4hana-inconsistency.jpg" alt="Why SAP???" /></p>

<p>What does the dialog titles <strong>“Hit List 17 Entries”</strong> and <strong>“Table Row 40 Entries”</strong> tell me? Nothing! 
This is from transaction VA02 (edit sales order) for Inco Terms (left) and Payment Terms (right). I wonder why something like this shipped in the first place and why it was not considered a bug in every single release that went out the door since then.</p>

<p>There are three films and three tv shows with the name “The Hit List”, but I doubt SAP is referring to any of them …</p>

<p><img src="/assets/The_Hit_List.jpeg" alt="The Hit List" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sap" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I know that I am complaining about small, minor things here, but please explain me this: What does the dialog titles “Hit List 17 Entries” and “Table Row 40 Entries” tell me? Nothing! This is from transaction VA02 (edit sales order) for Inco Terms (left) and Payment Terms (right). I wonder why something like this shipped in the first place and why it was not considered a bug in every single release that went out the door since then.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/20/notYourFamily.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-20T21:42:28+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-20T21:42:28+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/20/notYourFamily</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/20/notYourFamily.html"><![CDATA[<p>Why do many companies say <strong>“we are like a big family”</strong>? I can’t choose my family, but I can choose my employer. I want my company to be like a <strong><em>community</em></strong>, a group of people I join not because I need to, but because I want to!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="business" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why do many companies say “we are like a big family”? I can’t choose my family, but I can choose my employer. I want my company to be like a community, a group of people I join not because I need to, but because I want to!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two Types of Developers</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/development/2022/04/20/two-types-of-developers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Types of Developers" /><published>2022-04-20T08:36:28+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-20T08:36:28+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/development/2022/04/20/two-types-of-developers</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/development/2022/04/20/two-types-of-developers.html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the plesure to work with two types of developers.</p>

<p><strong>Type one</strong> is doing what you ask them to do (at most). Sometimes not even that. As I am far away from being perfect, I make mistakes, I write imperfect tickets and specs. The result? Garbage in, garbage out.</p>

<p><strong>Type two</strong> is questioning what I ask them to do. They propose alternative solutions, they tell me when my tickets are shit and they convert my garbage into something useful.</p>

<p>I am thankful that I can work with type two at the moment.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="development" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had the plesure to work with two types of developers. Type one is doing what you ask them to do (at most). Sometimes not even that. As I am far away from being perfect, I make mistakes, I write imperfect tickets and specs. The result? Garbage in, garbage out. Type two is questioning what I ask them to do. They propose alternative solutions, they tell me when my tickets are shit and they convert my garbage into something useful. I am thankful that I can work with type two at the moment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/fun/2022/04/20/how-i-experience-the-web-today.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-20T08:32:28+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-20T08:32:28+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/fun/2022/04/20/how-i-experience-the-web-today</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/fun/2022/04/20/how-i-experience-the-web-today.html"><![CDATA[<p>Disable your ad blocker and go to this side to see how the web works today: <a href="https://how-i-experience-web-today.com/">https://how-i-experience-web-today.com/</a>.</p>

<p>Sad, but true …</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="fun" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Disable your ad blocker and go to this side to see how the web works today: https://how-i-experience-web-today.com/. Sad, but true …]]></summary></entry></feed>