<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-04T18:37:46+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">alexander ilg microblog</title><subtitle>Just some things that come to my mind</subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/ux/2022/05/04/native-vs-electron-apps.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-05-04T17:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T17:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/ux/2022/05/04/native-vs-electron-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/ux/2022/05/04/native-vs-electron-apps.html"><![CDATA[<p>I don’t understand why so many people dislike <strong>Electron</strong> apps. I am writting this post in one - <strong><em>Visual Studio Code</em></strong>. Yes, native is great, but I fully understand companies that target Windows and the Mac to go the Electron way. 
<!--more--></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ux" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t understand why so many people dislike Electron apps. I am writting this post in one - Visual Studio Code. Yes, native is great, but I fully understand companies that target Windows and the Mac to go the Electron way.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How can I find the Sales Area information for a business partner in SAP?</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/sap/2022/05/04/howToFindSalesAreaDataForABusinessPartnerSAPGUI.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How can I find the Sales Area information for a business partner in SAP?" /><published>2022-05-04T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/sap/2022/05/04/howToFindSalesAreaDataForABusinessPartnerSAPGUI</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/sap/2022/05/04/howToFindSalesAreaDataForABusinessPartnerSAPGUI.html"><![CDATA[<p>Follow the following steps in the SAP GUI.<br />
<!--more--></p>
<ol>
  <li>Go to transaction <strong>BP</strong></li>
  <li>Enter the business partner number or search for the partner by other criteria.<br />
<img src="/assets/bp01.png" alt="SAP GUI Transaction BP" /></li>
  <li>After selecting the start button, you will see the matching business partners in the table below. Double-click on the one you want to open.</li>
  <li>When you are on the business partner details dialog, check the field <strong>Display in BP role</strong>. If <strong>Customer</strong> is not selected, please do so.<br />
<img src="/assets/bp02.png" alt="SAP GUI Transaction BP" /></li>
  <li>When Customer is selected, the button <strong><em>Sales and Distribution</em></strong> is visible. Select it.<br />
<img src="/assets/bp03.png" alt="SAP GUI Transaction BP" /></li>
  <li>On the Sales and Distribution dialog you will find the section <strong><em>Sales Area</em></strong>, where you will find the required information.<br />
<img src="/assets/bp04.png" alt="SAP GUI Transaction BP" /></li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="SAP" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Follow the following steps in the SAP GUI.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/travel/2022/04/29/berlin-april-2022.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-29T08:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-29T08:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/travel/2022/04/29/berlin-april-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/travel/2022/04/29/berlin-april-2022.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="berlin-april-2022">Berlin, April 2022</h2>
<p><img src="/assets/berlin-april.jpg" alt="Berlin" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin, April 2022]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/news/2022/04/29/reeder.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-29T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-29T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/news/2022/04/29/reeder</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/news/2022/04/29/reeder.html"><![CDATA[<p>I consume most of my news via RSS feeds and I use <a href="https://reeder.app">Reeder</a> on Mac and iOS.<br />
<img src="/assets/reeder.png" alt="Reeder" /><br />
With the latest version it is possible to add YouTube channels, Twitter and Reddit. Now all my news are finally in one place.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I consume most of my news via RSS feeds and I use Reeder on Mac and iOS. With the latest version it is possible to add YouTube channels, Twitter and Reddit. Now all my news are finally in one place.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/knowledgebase/2022/04/29/document360.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-29T01:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-29T01:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/knowledgebase/2022/04/29/document360</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/knowledgebase/2022/04/29/document360.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am playing around with <a href="https://document360.io">document360.io</a> at the moment, a tool to create internal and external <strong>knowledge bases</strong>. Looks cool, markdown support, Word import - I like what I see.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="knowledgebase" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am playing around with document360.io at the moment, a tool to create internal and external knowledge bases. Looks cool, markdown support, Word import - I like what I see.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/henryford/2022/04/28/do-not-give-users-what-they-want.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-28T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-28T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/henryford/2022/04/28/do-not-give-users-what-they-want</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/henryford/2022/04/28/do-not-give-users-what-they-want.html"><![CDATA[<p>The best solution is not to give users what they want, but to give them something that they did not even know was possible.
<img src="/assets/faster-horses.jpg" alt="ford" />
If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses. Henry Ford</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="HenryFord" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best solution is not to give users what they want, but to give them something that they did not even know was possible. If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses. Henry Ford]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/peace/2022/04/27/berlin-april-2022.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-04-27T21:00:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T21:00:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/peace/2022/04/27/berlin-april-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/peace/2022/04/27/berlin-april-2022.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="berlin-27th-april-2022">Berlin, 27th April 2022</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/berlin_2022-04-27.jpg" alt="Berlin Wall" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="peace" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin, 27th April 2022]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">With the small VW ID.3 to Berlin</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/electric/2022/04/27/With-VW-ID3-to-Berlin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="With the small VW ID.3 to Berlin" /><published>2022-04-27T18:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T18:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/electric/2022/04/27/With-VW-ID3-to-Berlin</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/electric/2022/04/27/With-VW-ID3-to-Berlin.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I drove with my <strong>VW ID.3</strong> from Augsburg to Berlin. About 600 km with just two charging stops.</p>

<p>In general, the car - even with the small 58kW battery - can perform on such a distance. There are just a few things that I don’t like: (1) The main display on the dashboard looks like it belongs to a toy car. No sign of the elegance of a Tesla, Audi or BMW. (2) When I set the speed to 100 km/h, it constantly switches: 99 to 100 to 99 to 100 to … it drives me crazy. (3) The way the doors are locked. I don’t get it - I always must press the button on the car key multiple times before the charging port opens or I am able to open the trunk.</p>

<p>Other than that, the car is just fine.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="electric" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I drove with my VW ID.3 from Augsburg to Berlin. About 600 km with just two charging stops. In general, the car - even with the small 58kW battery - can perform on such a distance. There are just a few things that I don’t like: (1) The main display on the dashboard looks like it belongs to a toy car. No sign of the elegance of a Tesla, Audi or BMW. (2) When I set the speed to 100 km/h, it constantly switches: 99 to 100 to 99 to 100 to … it drives me crazy. (3) The way the doors are locked. I don’t get it - I always must press the button on the car key multiple times before the charging port opens or I am able to open the trunk. Other than that, the car is just fine.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">People Business</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/25/people-business.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People Business" /><published>2022-04-25T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-25T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/25/people-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/business/2022/04/25/people-business.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am developing, selling, and implementing software since more than 20 years. During that time, I participated in many requests for proposal, many sales pitches and I competed against a lot of competitors. You might think that the best software always wins, but that is not the case. Many times, I heard things like <strong><em>“we choose you because you made the most competent impression”</em></strong> or <strong><em>“you worked hardest during the POC”</em></strong>.</p>

<p>This shows that it is at least 50% people business. Your impression as a software provider is as important as your software. I learned this very early in my career. I was hired by a company in Cologne, Germany to evaluate several e-commerce providers for a new website - among them Oracle and SAP. After the evaluation it was clear to me that Oracle has the far better software based on J2EE, while SAP was pitching it proprietary ITS technology. At the end they still went with SAP. Why? Because the sales pitch was superior to the one from Oracle (they showed up totally unprepared) and the CIO told me <strong><em>“The way they showed up here and pitched the solutions, the same way they will do the implementation. I have no good feeling with Oracle”</em></strong>.</p>

<p>I think that I make a good impression most of the time and I see that as a competitive advantage. COVID hurt in that regard, as there were no face-to-face meetings. Let’s hope we are soon back to onsite sales demos.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/corona.jpg" alt="Corona" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="business" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am developing, selling, and implementing software since more than 20 years. During that time, I participated in many requests for proposal, many sales pitches and I competed against a lot of competitors. You might think that the best software always wins, but that is not the case. Many times, I heard things like “we choose you because you made the most competent impression” or “you worked hardest during the POC”. This shows that it is at least 50% people business. Your impression as a software provider is as important as your software. I learned this very early in my career. I was hired by a company in Cologne, Germany to evaluate several e-commerce providers for a new website - among them Oracle and SAP. After the evaluation it was clear to me that Oracle has the far better software based on J2EE, while SAP was pitching it proprietary ITS technology. At the end they still went with SAP. Why? Because the sales pitch was superior to the one from Oracle (they showed up totally unprepared) and the CIO told me “The way they showed up here and pitched the solutions, the same way they will do the implementation. I have no good feeling with Oracle”. I think that I make a good impression most of the time and I see that as a competitive advantage. COVID hurt in that regard, as there were no face-to-face meetings. Let’s hope we are soon back to onsite sales demos.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">jorganizer - first steps in Java</title><link href="alexander-ilg.github.io/backinthedays/2022/04/24/jorganizer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="jorganizer - first steps in Java" /><published>2022-04-24T02:42:42+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-24T02:42:42+02:00</updated><id>alexander-ilg.github.io/backinthedays/2022/04/24/jorganizer</id><content type="html" xml:base="alexander-ilg.github.io/backinthedays/2022/04/24/jorganizer.html"><![CDATA[<p>Until 2001 I was mainly developing in <strong>Perl</strong>, but I wanted to get into the <strong>Java</strong> space (which was a smart move, as it got me a job as Java developer at <strong>SAP</strong>).</p>

<p>How do you best learn a new language? Going through tutorials is only working until a certain point, then I need to get my hands dirty and do a real project.</p>

<p>In 2002, I started to write a webbased PIM with Java, running on a Tomcat server - it was called <strong>jorganizer</strong> and I shared it on SourceForge. The <a href="http://jorganizer.sourceforge.net/index.html">website</a> is still up today, but I didn’t touch it the last 20 years.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/jorganizer.jpg" alt="jorganizer" /></p>

<p>This was at a time when we dealed with <strong>Microsoft Internet Explorer</strong> and <strong>Netscape Navigator</strong>, a time where PNG was not yet available. At least I am sure it is not using <strong><em>Log4J</em></strong> ;-)</p>

<p>I wonder if the code would still run today on a modern tomcat.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="backinthedays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Until 2001 I was mainly developing in Perl, but I wanted to get into the Java space (which was a smart move, as it got me a job as Java developer at SAP). How do you best learn a new language? Going through tutorials is only working until a certain point, then I need to get my hands dirty and do a real project. In 2002, I started to write a webbased PIM with Java, running on a Tomcat server - it was called jorganizer and I shared it on SourceForge. The website is still up today, but I didn’t touch it the last 20 years. This was at a time when we dealed with Microsoft Internet Explorer and Netscape Navigator, a time where PNG was not yet available. At least I am sure it is not using Log4J ;-) I wonder if the code would still run today on a modern tomcat.]]></summary></entry></feed>